<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>GZ</title>
    <link>https://zorzi.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on GZ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zorzi.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pent-up Frustration 2</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/posts/jane_street/jane_2022_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/posts/jane_street/jane_2022_11/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the solution of the November&amp;rsquo;s Jane Street puzzle. It involves pentagons, patience and a lot of computation. Check out the original post on the Jane Street website.
The Puzzle The scope of this puzzle is to find the minimum distance between two pentagons arranged in a polyform.
You have seventeen identical unit regular pentagonal tiles on a tabletop. You arrange them all into a single polyform, so each pentagon placed after the first shares a side with an already-placed pentagon, but no two pentagons overlap other than along their boundaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jane Street Puzzles</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/posts/jane_street/puzzles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/posts/jane_street/puzzles/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered the website Jane Street. They are a quantitative trading firm that hires people with a strong mathematical background. They also publish monthly challenges in the form of puzzles. If you solve the puzzle, you can submit your solution and if correct, they will publish your name on the puzzle&amp;rsquo;s page.
The first one I tackled was Pent-up Frustration 2.
I also publish the code on GitHub (once the solution is out).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 12:49:21 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Puzzles Do you like puzzles? I do!
You can find some puzzles here
About this site Do you want to see how I built this site? Check out this post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this site</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/posts/about_this_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 12:19:59 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/posts/about_this_site/</guid>
      <description>This site is built using Hugo, a very fast static site generator built in golang that translates markdown files into websites.
Theme The base theme I am using is PaperMod but I heavily modified it to fit my needs.
Link Checker To make sure all the links are working, I use hydra. This runs as a Github Action and scrapes the website for broken links.
Source Code You can take a look at the source code on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 10:49:49 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/hello/</guid>
      <description>Hi! Nice to see you here I am Giorgio Zorzi, a tech enthusiast. I work as a software developer / tech lead located in UAE.
You are most welcome to say hello -&amp;gt; giorgio@zorzi.dev</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bachelor</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/education/bachelor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/education/bachelor/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybrik</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/experience/cybrik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/experience/cybrik/</guid>
      <description>Led technical strategic planning, including roadmap development and end-to-end sprint management. Led the development and design of end-to-end, high quality software, complex technical prototypes and delivered the MVP for Cybrik AI, a cloud-based (Azure) enterprise platform with a React.js front end, a Python back end and data ingestion using Apache Airflow. Designed and implemented the document search functionalities using Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing (NLP) techniques reducing the time for our customers to find the relevant information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenwich</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/experience/greenwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/experience/greenwich/</guid>
      <description>Awarded a scholarship sponsored by the EU throughout the duration of the research internship which was part of my Master’s Degree dissertation.
Contributed to the study of the separation of impurities in melted silicon using electromagnetic induction Developed and acquired skills in conducting simulations using Finite Element Methods </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livanova</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/experience/livanova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/experience/livanova/</guid>
      <description>Consulted and project-managed the Greenhouse Gas (GHG) reporting cycle for three consecutive years for LivaNova Plc, a Nasdaq-listed medical device manufacturing company, with 9 production sites across various countries. Identified opportunities for improvement in GHG reporting following a gap analysis, review and health-check of previous reports. Prepared and presented findings to the LivaNova Board of Directors highlighting opportunities for improvement and optimization. Worked with external auditors and senior management to ensure timely delivery of an accurate and comprehensive GHG report to the LivaNova Board of Directors for the approval prior to submission to the UK Regulator and disclosure in the Annual Report to shareholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/education/master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/education/master/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onyx</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/experience/onyx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/experience/onyx/</guid>
      <description>Selected to join ONYX Insights on a fixed-term project to apply data mining techniques and statistical analysis to extract data from wind turbines. Analysed complex datasets using Natural Language Processing techniques. Applied Machine Learning techniques, transforming raw data into valuable insights. Created Graphical User Interface for data visualisation, creating a time savings for the final users of up to 90%. Strengthened proficiency in Python and ability to write standardised code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORE_Catapult</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/experience/ore_catapult/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/experience/ore_catapult/</guid>
      <description> Developed algorithm using MATLAB Simulink used for capital budgeting and estimation of the profitability of potential investments that optimises a Battery Storage System and maximises the Internal Rate of Return. Developed commercial awareness and strengthened technical knowledge of algorithm development. Offered a full-time position as a Research Engineer. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phd</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/experience/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/experience/phd/</guid>
      <description>“Improved Yield from Wind Turbines through online anomaly detection and compensation”
Identified new and innovative ways of extracting data from wind turbines to maximise energy production. Developed research proposing new ways of maximising energy production whilst reducing costs. Advanced project management and time management skills. Furthered research and technical knowledge as well as commercial awareness in the field of wind and renewable energy. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/education/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/education/phd/</guid>
      <description>Awarded an annual £14,000 grant for four consecutive years of PhD studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SSE</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/experience/sse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/experience/sse/</guid>
      <description> Designed MATLAB algorithm to characterise the Wind Turbine Power Curves in an innovative way using SCADA data, substantially reducing the time required for data cleaning and achieving improved efficiency. Consolidated technical knowledge of algorithm development and strengthened project management skills </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TA</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/experience/ta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/experience/ta/</guid>
      <description> Served as Teaching Assistant for the Graduate Programme in Wind, Solar and Hydro Energy. Assisted Lecturers in the delivery of the course; held tutorials and prepared teaching materials. Mentored undergraduate students. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Techstars</title>
      <link>https://zorzi.dev/experience/techstars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zorzi.dev/experience/techstars/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
